{"tossups": [{"question": "This political party was created by the Tamworth Manifesto, which aimed to distinguish it from the Duke of Wellington\u2019s government. A leader of this party gave the Winds of Change speech in South Africa, signaling decolonization that included this party\u2019s suppression of the Mau Mau Rebellion. A leader of this party nicknamed \u201cMilk Snatcher\u201d won a war over the Falklands Islands, and it allied with the DUP in 2016 under Theresa May. For ten points, name this British political party opposed by the Labour Party.", "answer": "<b> Conservative</b> Party", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This man served as the second and final U.S. Secretary for Foreign Affairs. This man once joked that he could travel through the country by the lights of people burning him in effigy after he negotiated a treaty that provided for the removal of British troops from forts in the Northwest Territory. This author of five of the Federalist Papers is this namesake of a 1795 treaty with Great Britain. For ten points, name this first Chief Justice of the Supreme Court.", "answer": "John<b> Jay</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "The Ottoman Empire first conquered this modern-day country by defeating the forces of Tuman Bay II at the Battle of Ridaniya. A Muslim state based in this country was ruled by the Bahri and Burji Dynasties. Muhammad Ali declared himself Khedive of this country under the Ottoman Empire, and established this country\u2019s cotton industry. The capital of the Mamluk Sultanate was in, for ten points, what country that has been ruled from the cities of Fustat and Cairo?", "answer": "<b> Egypt</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Description acceptable. This policy was first reported in 2002 by<em> The Hill</em> and made news again in March 2017 in an Ashley Parker profile of the former Karen Batten. This policy\u2019s ideological precedent is the Modesto Manifesto, leading some reporters to dub it the Billy Graham Rule. Critics of this policy, which includes rules regarding alcohol, work, and dining partners, argue that its application in the Governor\u2019s office in Indianapolis and the White House constitutes sexual discrimination. For ten points, identify this personal code of the Vice President.", "answer": "Mike<b> Pence</b>\u2019s rule(s) regarding behavior with<b> women</b> (accept descriptions of Mike<b> Pence</b>\u2019s rule against<b> dining alone with women</b> who aren\u2019t his wife,<b> Pence</b>\u2019s rule against<b> working late with women</b>, and/or<b> Pence</b>\u2019s rule against attending events with<b> alcohol without his wife</b> being present; prompt on partial answers, such as \u201cpolicy toward women\u201d or \u201cMike Pence\u2019s personal code\u201d)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "This scientist disproved Lavoisier\u2019s definition of acids being elements that contain oxygen. This man injured himself while working with nitrogen trichloride, which led to him hiring Michael Faraday as an assistant. This scientist experimented on himself with nitrous oxide, realizing that it could be used as an anesthetic that he nicknamed \u201claughing gas.\u201d For ten points, name this English scientist who discovered elements like calcium, iodine, and chlorine.", "answer": "Sir Humphry<b> Davy</b>", "metadata": "Science - Chemistry"}, {"question": "These places are required to tolerate, but not promote, disagreeable speech due to the case<em> Hazelwood</em> <em>v. Kuhlmeier</em>. The speech rights of black-armband wearing people in one of these places was the subject of the case<em> Tinker v. Des Moines</em>.<em> Swann v. Charlotte-Mecklenburg</em> ruled that these places could be desegregated via busing. For ten points, name these public institutions whose \u201cseparate but equal\u201d status was banned by<em> Brown v. Board of Education</em>.", "answer": "public<b> school</b>s (accept answers related to elementary, middle, and/or high<b> school</b>s; do not accept answers related to colleges or universities)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Because Richard Lawrence believed that he held this position, he attempted to assassinate president Andrew Jackson and was thereafter confined to an insane asylum. FDR held a publicized hot dog dinner with the holder of this position in June, 1939. John Dickinson was the primary author of a document addressed to the holder of this position, which urged him to reconsider tax provisions over the American colonies. For ten points, the Olive Branch Petition was addressed to the holder of what position, George III?", "answer": "<b> King of England</b> (accept equivalents such as the<b> British monarch</b>; prompt on partial answers such as \u201cking\u201d or \u201cleader of the United Kingdom of Great Britain and (Northern) Ireland\u201d)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "A Frank Gehry-designed memorial to this man controversially plans to include a tapestry of stainless steel cables, which may depict peaceful imagery of France or Kansas. Statues planned for this man\u2019s memorial include a group inspired by a photo of this man instructing the 101st Airborne Division on June 5th, 1944. In 2017, officials celebrated the groundbreaking of a long-planned memorial for, for ten points, what Supreme Commander of Allied Forces during World War II and US President?", "answer": "Dwight D.<b> Eisenhower</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Description acceptable. During this event, the CRS prevented citizens from crossing a river; they then built barracades instead. Daniel Cohn-Bendit [ben-deet] led one faction during this event, in which the president claimed \u201cnobody attacks an empty palace\u201d before fleeing the country. The Grenelle Agreements attempted to resolve this event, which was preceded by the Movement of 22 March, whose members occupied a portion of Nanterre. Protests at the Arc de Triomphe and the Sorbonne were a part of, for ten points, what massive period of civil unrest in France in the late 1960s?", "answer": "<b> May</b> 19<b>68</b> student protests (or accept any two of the three underlined parts of \u201c<b>student </b>protests against Charles<b> de Gaulle</b> in May 19<b>68</b>\u201d; prompt on partial answers)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This scandal was carried out by middlemen Adnan Khashoggi and Manucher Ghorbanifar. As part of this scandal, secretary Fawn Hall shredded evidence of violations of the Boland Amendment. This scandal was investigated by the Tower Commission and led to indictments for Caspar Weinberger and John Poindexter, who had aided in the funding of an anti-Sandinista force abroad. For ten points, name this Reagan-era scandal in which funds from arms sales to the Middle East were redirected to aid rebels in Nicaragua.", "answer": "<b> Iran-Contra</b> scandal (or affair, etc.; prompt on partial answers)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "During this war, Charles Hay\u2019s troops toasted his enemies and asked them to fire first; Maurice de Saxe prevailed over the Duke of Cumberland in that Battle of Fontenoy. Disagreements over whether Charles VI could violate Salic law in proclaiming his heir helped prompt this war, which began when Silesia was invaded by Frederick the Great of Prussia. For ten points, name this 1740 war over Maria Theresa\u2019s succession to a Habsburg throne.", "answer": "War of the<b> Austrian Succession</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This event began when Lucius Cimber presented a petition to return his brother from exile. Security forces failed to reach this event in time, even though Servilius Casca had leaked its details. This event triggered the Liberator\u2019s Civil War, in which the perpetrator Cassius was hunted down by the Second Triumvirate. Outside the Theater of Pompey, this event\u2019s target may have cried \u201cet tu, Brute?\u201d [broo-tay] as he was stabbed. For ten points, name this 44 BC event in which a dictator of Rome was killed.", "answer": "<b> assassination</b> (or<b> murder</b>,<b> stabbing</b>, etc.) of<b> Julius Caesar</b>", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {"question": "Jews living under this empire were recruited into cantonist schools and forced to complete years of military service. Menahim Beilis was accused by this empire\u2019s officials of murdering a young boy and dumping his body near a brick factory, as related in Bernard Malamud\u2019s novel<em> The Fixer</em>. The Pale of Settlement was created to house Jews by a female ruler of this empire. For ten points, name this empire which allowed some Jews to serve on the Duma under Nicholas II.", "answer": "<b> Russia</b>n Empire", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "Near the end of this film, a man indicates his support for the main character by wiping the sweat off of his brow using his handkerchief. Lily James portrays a secretary in this film whose primary job is to type dictated letters and speeches. In this film, Viscount Halifax threatens to resign his cabinet position unless the Prime Minister agrees to peace talks with Nazi Germany. For ten points, name this 2017 film set in May 1940, named for a famous speech of Winston Churchill.", "answer": "<b> Darkest Hour</b> (do not accept additional information)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Film"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This period was mitigated by the creation of shelterbelts by the Forestry Service. This period received its name after Robert Geiger\u2019s visit to Boise City on the Sunday of April 14 coincided with an incidence of\u201cblack blizzards.\u201d Dorothea Lange\u2019s photograph<em> Migrant Mother</em> became symbolic of this period\u2019s mass displacement of \u201cOkies\u201d who traveled to California after facing crop failure. For ten points, name this period of the 1930s in which severe drought affected the American plains.", "answer": "<b> Dust Bowl</b> (prompt on Great Depression before \u201cGeiger\u201d is read)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>During this event, Lieutenant Braunersreuther [brown-ers-roy-ter] demanded a surrender within 30 minutes and received it 29 minutes later. At the outset of this event, Captain Henry Glass was surprised to find only a Japanese merchant ship in port. The victims of</b> <b>this event, lacking proper guns in (+)</b> <b>Fort Santa Cruz, rowed to the USS</b><em><b> Charleston</b></em><b> to</b> <b>verbally return what they thought was a salute, because they were unaware that the US had (*) </b> declared war on Spain. Only warning shots were fired during, for ten points, what bloodless 1898 event in which a western Pacific island changed hands?", "answer": "<b> capture</b> (or<b> invasion</b>,<b> attack</b>,<b> surrender</b>, etc.) of<b> Guam</b> during the Spanish-American War (prompt on partial answers; prompt on the Spanish-American War before \u201cSpain\u201d is read)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>An essay by Simone Weil claims that the central theme of a poem by this author is unbridled force and power. According to a tradition known as the Certamen, Hesiod won a bronze tripod in a (+) poetry contest against this man. Richmond Lattimore is best known for his translations of this man\u2019s works, one of which begins by describing the rage of (*) </b>Achilles when his concubine is seized by Agamemnon. For ten points, name this blind Greek poet who wrote about the Trojan War in the<em> Iliad</em>.", "answer": "<b> Homer</b>", "metadata": "Mythology - Mythology"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>A leader of this nation was militarily supported by the Safari Club in fighting the first Shaba conflict. Another leader of this country was executed by a firing squad commanded</b> <b>by Moises (+)</b> <b>Tshombe; that ruler was deposed after calling in Soviet aid to suppress</b> <b>the secession of its Katanga provinces. Another leader of this country tried to promote (*)</b>\u201c<em>authenticit\u00b4e</em>\u201d by wearing the<em> abacost</em> and renaming his country Zaire. For ten points, name this country once ruled by Patrice Lumumba and Mobutu Sese Seko from Kinshasa.", "answer": "<b> Democratic Republic of the Congo</b> (accept<b> DRC</b>; accept<b> Zaire</b>; prompt on Congo; do not accept or prompt on Republic of the Congo)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>A man with this surname was supported by a group of New Hampshire college students</b> <b>who shaved and showered. The initiative \u201cClean for Gene\u201d supported (+)</b> <b>Eugene, a</b> <b>1968 Democratic candidate with this surname from Minnesota. The Tydings Committee investigated claims made by a senator with this surname, including that the (*) </b> State Department contained numerous \u201cloyalty risks\u201d and \u201ccard carrying communists.\u201d For ten points, give this surname of Wisconsin senator Joseph, a leading figure in the 1950s Red Scare.", "answer": "<b> McCarthy</b> (accept Eugene<b> McCarthy</b>; accept Joseph<b> McCarthy</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}], "bonuses": []}